# CHRISTOPHE FOYER

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com
United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • United Kingdom: (+44) 7444 175493
US and French citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

## **SUMMARY:**

Mechanical Design Engineer with experience in projects in involving mechatronics and software development. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

- CAD, FEA and CFD
- Prototyping and Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)
- Engineering Hand Calculations
- Embedded Systems and Software Development

### **EDUCATION:**

#### **Washington University in Saint Louis**

Saint Louis, USA

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

Aug 2014 - Dec 2017

y **Abroad:** - RWTH Aachen, Germany (Summer 2017) – Energy & Mechatronics

- SIT Iceland (Summer 2015) – Energy Engineering and Economics

Lycée Sainte Marie

Caen, France Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

French Baccalauréat with honours - Science track

# **EXPERIENCE:**

# **Temporary Works Design (TWD)**

London, United Kingdom Nov 2018 – Present

Design Engineer

TWD is an engineering company specialized in creating custom-designed tools and structures to perform

- transport and installation projects.
  Design of bespoke equipment and structures for civil engineering contractors using Autodesk Inventor
- Verification of structural parameters using engineering hand calculations and finite element analysis

**Tata Steel Europe** 

Ijmuiden, Netherlands

Mechanical Engineering Intern – Student SWAT Team

Apr 2018 – July 2018

Tata Steel is Europe's second largest steel producer, with steelmaking in the UK and Netherlands, and manufacturing plants across Europe.

- Successfully built a large-scale thermal simulation in Python reducing temperature estimation error by 82.4%
- Proof-of-concept enabling potential savings of around one million euros per year if implemented into production
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

# Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

Co-Founder

WUDBF is an aerospace-oriented engineering team that attends yearly competitions that are sponsored by the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA).

- Co-led the team to 12<sup>th</sup> place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

# **SKILLS:**

CAD / FEA / CFD SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, XFLR5, RFEM
Programming Python, MATLAB, Simulink, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite wet layup (FG/CF), 3D-Printing, GD&T
Software / OS
Microsoft Office Suite, LaTeX, Windows, Linux
Native English and French (Bilingual) • Basic German and Icelandic

<sup>\*</sup>References available upon request

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS:**

# Senior Design Project – Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%

## **INDEPENDENT PROJECTS:**

resume.cfoyer.com/#projects

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018 **FDM Tricopter** 

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing and electrical systems integration.

Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Inventor and Netfabb

**Motor Test Stand** Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly.

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new Windows installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

**Electric Longboard** Oct 2016 - Dec 2017

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard.

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminum and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations

# **IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation**

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media centre system for personal use.

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (with added support for Windows and OSX)
- Control over house appliances and interfacing with Open Source Media Center (OSMC)

Dec 2013 - Jan 2015 **Robotics Test Platform** 

Coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing.

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over IP
- Experiments in visual odometry using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

# **Volunteering and Work Experience:**

Event Planner

Seasonal farm hand

## **American Society of Mechanical Engineers**

Washington University in St. Louis

Sep 2016 – May 2017

Researched and presented to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus for \$45,000; secured a date for his visit

Advised ASME members with ongoing projects on manufacturing and component selection.

Domaine du Vivier Le Mesnil Mauger, France

Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work

Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer

**ICC** Ishinomaki, Japan May 2014 Volunteer

Construction of wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.

Jun 2015 - Aug 2017